Konrad and Florence Ballin Cramer
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Photographs, 1906-1960, undated, Series 7:; (Box 7; 0.5 linear feet)
  - Woodstock People, circa 1909-1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
    (pictured are Gene Speicher, John Carlson, Andrew Dasburg, Harry Hopkins, Came and Ella Lasher, Charles Rosen, Clarence Bolton, and others unidentified)
  - Woodstock Parties, 1946-1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
    (pictured are Alexander Brook, Joe Pollett, Tom Penning, Helen Estes, Elsa Kimball, Sid Berkowitz, Dick Burlingame, Herman Cherry, Charles Rosen, John Striebel, Sigmund Menkes, Zombie Pachner, Sam Eskin, Florine Walkowitz, Kaj Klitgaard, Marianne Mecklin, Jay Allen, Odillon, Gene Speicher, Arnold Blanch, Edward L. Chase, Henry Mattson, Fanny Ganso, Yasuo Kuniyoshi, Karl Fortess, and many others)
  - Woodstock Views, circa 1909, undated, (2 folders, including copy print) (Box 7, Folder 53-54)
  - Early Woodstock Views and Figures, circa 1900s (Box 7, Folder 55)
    (figure may be Florence Ballin)
  - Color and College Experiments by Konrad Cramer, undated (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Travel Snapshots, 1934, undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Photo Postcards, circa 1934 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Works of Art (unfilmed) (Box 7)
    - Installation Views, 1931-1953, undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Konrad Cramer (1915-1957, undated), undated (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Florence Ballin Cramer (1929-1944, undated), undated, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 62-63)
    - Other Artists, 1935, 1958, undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
- Artwork, 1897-1954, undated, Series 8:; (Boxes 8-11; 1.2 linear feet)
  This series contains sketchbooks, loose sketches and drawings, original illustrations for children's picture books, textile designs, graphic designs, woodblock and linoleum block prints, printing blocks, examples of textile prints and batik, calligraphy, and an autograph book kept by Florence Ballin as a child containing artwork, poems, and music by its signers. Most of the artwork is by Konrad and Florence Ballin Cramer. Artwork by others is filed separately. Artwork is in pencil, graphite, watercolor, gouache, pastel.
  Additional sketches by Florence Ballin Cramer can be found in the Writings series. Examples of woodblock and linoleum prints and engravings by the Cramers and others in their circle can be found in Printed Materials. Other sketches are found in the account books in Personal Business Records. See series descriptions for more details.
  Most of the artwork in this series was previously microfilmed in an earlier arrangement on reel 2755.
  - Sketchbooks (Box 8)
    - Konrad Cramer (Box 8)
      - circa 1906-1908 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - circa 1907 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - circa 1909 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - after 1912 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - 1916, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Dismantled Design Sketchbook, circa 1918, 1920, 1924, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
        (Original Collation)
      - Sketchbook with Notes on Printmaking, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Florence Ballin Cramer, undated, (2 volumes in 2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    - Aileen Cramer (daughter), 1942 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Unsigned, 1909, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Sketches and Drawings (Box 8)
    - Konrad Cramer (Box 8)
      - 1921, 1923, 1954, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Blackface Cartoons, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
      - Erotic Drawings, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Florence Ballin Cramer, 1925, 1938, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Childhood Drawings of Aileen and Margot Cramer, 1924, 1926, undated (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
    - Caricature of Mayor Goltz of Woodstock by Aimé Titus, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Children's Books by Konrad and Florence Ballin Cramer (Box 8)
    - Thoughts and Pictures, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 22-23)
    - A Book for Very Small Children, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Textile Designs, circa 1918, (4 folders; see also Box 9 and OV 11) (Box 8, Folder 25-28)
  - Designs for Hue and Cry, 1923, undated, (See OV 10) (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Wood and Linoleum Block Prints by the Cramers, undated, (2 folders, including duplicates) (Box 8, Folder 30-31)
  - Printing Blocks by the Cramers, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 32-33)
    (see also Konrad Cramer's 1916, 1921 Sketchbook for 2 original bookplate printing blocks)
  - Woodblock Prints by Children, 1920-1921 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Textile Samples Designed by Konrad Cramer, circa 1915-1916 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Undyed Batik made by Konrad Cramer, undated, (see also OV 11) (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Calligraphy, 1923, 1925, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Miscellaneous Designs, Sketches, and Prints, undated, (See also OV 10) (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Autograph Book of Florence Ballin Cramer, 1897-1899 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    (Contains paintings, drawings, poems, and music by signers)
  - Oversized Textile Designs (See Box 8, f28) (Box 9 (sol))
  - Oversized Artwork (see Box 8, f29 and 38) (Box 10 (OV))
  - Oversized Artwork (See Box 8, f28 and 36) (Box 11 (OV))